<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38619053</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vestibular migraine: an update.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>252</StartPage><EndPage>263</EndPage><MedlinePgn>252-263</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001257</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">We performed a narrative review of the recent findings in epidemiology, clinical presentation, mechanisms and treatment of vestibular migraine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Vestibular migraine is an underdiagnosed condition that has a high prevalence among general, headache and neuro-otology clinics. Vestibular migraine has a bimodal presentation probably associated with a hormonal component in women. These patients could have a complex clinical phenotype including concomitant autonomic, inflammatory or connective tissue conditions that have a higher prevalence of psychological symptoms, which may mistakenly lead to a diagnosis of a functional neurological disorder. A high proportion of patients with postural perceptual persistent dizziness have a migraine phenotype. Independently of the clinical presentation and past medical history, patients with the vestibular migraine phenotype can respond to regular migraine preventive treatments, including those targeting the calcitonin gene-related peptide pathways.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Vestibular migraine is an underdiagnosed migraine phenotype that shares the pathophysiological mechanisms of migraine, with growing interest in recent years. A thorough anamnesis is essential to increase sensitivity in patients with unknown cause of dizziness and migraine treatment should be considered (see supplemental video-abstract).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Villar-Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Maria D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR King's Clinical Research Facility, SLaM Biomedical Research Centre and Wolfson Sensory Pain and Regeneration, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goadsby</LastName><ForeName>Peter J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR King's Clinical Research Facility, SLaM Biomedical Research Centre and Wolfson Sensory Pain and Regeneration, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004244" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dizziness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Migraine Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014717" MajorTopicYN="N">Vertigo</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015837" MajorTopicYN="N">Vestibular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>
<i>PJG reports, over the last 36 months, grants from Celgene and Kallyope, and personal fees from Aeon Biopharma, Abbvie, Amgen, eNeura, CoolTech LLC, Dr Reddys’, Eli-Lilly and Company, Epalex, Linpharma, Lundbeck, Man&amp;Science, Novartis, Pfizer, Sanofi, Satsuma, Shiratronics, and Teva Pharmaceuticals, and personal fees for advice through Gerson Lehrman Group, Guidepoint, SAI Med Partners, Vector Metric, and fees for educational materials from CME Outfitters, and publishing royalties or fees from Massachusetts Medical Society, Oxford University Press, UptoDate and Wolters Kluwer, and a patent magnetic stimulation for headache (No. WO2016090333 A1) assigned to eNeura without fee. M.D.V.M. has no conflicts of interest.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38619053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202406000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lempert T, Neuhauser H. Epidemiology of vertigo, migraine and vestibular migraine. J Neurol 2009; 256:333–338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19225823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calhoun AH, Ford S, Pruitt AP, Fisher KG. The point prevalence of dizziness or vertigo in migraine and factors that influence presentation. Headache 2011; 51:1388–1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21797862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang BC, Kim T, Kwon JK. Prevalence of vestibular migraine in an otolaryngologic clinic: preliminary clinical diagnosis versus diagnosis according to the strictly applied Bárány criteria. J Vestib Res 2023; 33:137–142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieterich M, Obermann M, Celebisoy N. Vestibular migraine: the most frequent entity of episodic vertigo. J Neurol 2016; 263: (Suppl 1): S82–S89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27083888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppert D, Brandt T. Descriptions of vestibular migraine and Menière's disease in Greek and Chinese antiquity. Cephalalgia 2017; 37:385–390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27129480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempert T, Olesen J, Furman J, et al. Vestibular migraine: diagnostic criteria. J Vestib Res 2012; 22:167–172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23142830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS). The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd edition. Cephalalgia. 2018; 38:1–211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ombergen A, Van Rompaey V, Van de Heyning P, Wuyts F. Vestibular migraine in an otolaryngology clinic: prevalence, associated symptoms, and prophylactic medication effectiveness. Otol Neurotol 2015; 36:133–138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25251304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reploeg MD, Goebel JA. Migraine-associated dizziness: patient characteristics and management options. Otol Neurotol 2002; 23:364–371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11981397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Çelik O, Tanyeri Toker G, Eskiizmir G, et al. The effectiveness of medical prophylactic treatment on vestibular migraine and its effect on the quality of life. J Int Adv Otol 2020; 16:28–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31347507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuhauser HK, von Brevern M, Radtke A, et al. Epidemiology of vestibular vertigo: a neurotologic survey of the general population. Neurology 2005; 65:898–904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16186531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akdal G, Baykan B, Ertaş M, et al. Population-based study of vestibular symptoms in migraineurs. Acta Otolaryngol 2015; 135:435–439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formeister EJ, Rizk HG, Kohn MA, Sharon JD. The epidemiology of vestibular migraine: a population-based survey study. Otol Neurotol 2018; 39:1037–1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30020261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho GF, Luedtke K, Pinheiro CF, et al. Migraine and balance impairment: influence of subdiagnosis, otoneurological function, falls, and psychosocial factors. Headache 2022; 62:548–557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35593785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Sohn SI, Jung DK, et al. Migraine and isolated recurrent vertigo of unknown cause. Neurol Res 2002; 24:663–665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12392202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akdal G, Ozge A, Ergor G. The prevalence of vestibular symptoms in migraine or tension-type headache. J Vestib Res 2013; 23:101–106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23788138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisdorff A, Andree C, Vaillant M, Sandor PS. Headache-associated dizziness in a headache population: prevalence and impact. Cephalalgia 2010; 30:815–820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenbussche N, Lastarria Perez C, Karsan N, Goadsby PJ. Analysis of vertigo in chronic migraine through extended phenotyping. Cephalalgia 2019; 39 (1S):90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furman JM, Marcus DA, Balaban CD. Vestibular migraine: clinical aspects and pathophysiology. Lancet Neurol 2013; 12:706–715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23769597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan M, Guo X, Liu W, et al. Temporal patterns of vertigo and migraine in vestibular migraine. Front Neurosci 2020; 14:341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Xu X, Qi W, et al. Vestibular migraine: the chameleon in vestibular disease. Neurol Sci 2021; 42:1719–1731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evers S. Did Martin Luther suffer from vestibular migraine? Eur J Neurol 2023; doi: 10.1111/ene.16085. [Epub ahead of print]. PMID: 37804126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11464391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37804126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Carpena P, Lopez-Escamez JA. Do we need to reconsider the classification of vestibular migraine? Expert Rev Neurother 2021; 21:503–516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallampalli MP, Rizk HG, Kheradmand A, et al. Care gaps and recommendations in vestibular migraine: an expert panel summit. Front Neurol 2021; 12:812678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8762211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayan A, Hood JD. Neuro-otological manifestations of migraine. Brain 1984; 107 (Pt 4):1123–1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6334543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Çelebisoy N, Ak AK, Ataç C, et al. Comparison of clinical features in patients with vestibular migraine and migraine. J Neurol 2023; 270:3567–3573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitty CW. Migraine without headache. Lancet 1967; 2:283–285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4165917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini P, Vannucchi P, Giannoni B, Pecci R. Epigone migraine vertigo (EMV): a late migraine equivalent. Acta Otorhinolaryngol Ital 2014; 34:62–70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3970230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause DN, Warfvinge K, Haanes KA, Edvinsson L. Hormonal influences in migraine - interactions of oestrogen, oxytocin and CGRP. Nat Rev Neurol 2021; 17:621–633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34545218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornello R, Caponnetto V, Frattale I, Sacco S. Patterns of migraine in postmenopausal women: a systematic review. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat 2021; 17:859–871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33776441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar-Martinez MD, Goadsby PJ. Pathophysiology and therapy of associated features of migraine. Cells 2022; 11:2767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9455236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36078174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo A, Marcelli V, Esposito F, et al. Abnormal thalamic function in patients with vestibular migraine. Neurology 2014; 82:2120–2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Zhou J, Guo M, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of voxel-based morphometric studies of migraine. J Neurol 2023; 270:152–170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36098838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhe X, Zhang H, Tang M, et al. Brain functional connectivity patterns associated with symptoms of vestibular migraine. Front Neurosci 2023; 17:1231273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38156263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang Y, Tian K, et al. Calcitonin gene-related peptide facilitates sensitization of the vestibular nucleus in a rat model of chronic migraine. J Headache Pain 2020; 21:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang Y, Wang Y, et al. Inhibition of glutamatergic trigeminal nucleus caudalis- vestibular nucleus projection neurons attenuates vestibular dysfunction in the chronic-NTG model of migraine. J Headache Pain 2023; 24:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37386456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Ajona D, Villar-Martinez MD, Goadsby PJ. Targets for migraine treatment: beyond calcitonin gene-related peptide. Curr Opin Neurol 2021; 34:363–372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeets MC, Vernooy CB, Souverijn JH, Ferrari MD. Intracellular and plasma magnesium in familial hemiplegic migraine and migraine with and without aura. Cephalalgia 1994; 14:29–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8200020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beh SC, Masrour S, Smith SV, Friedman DI. Clinical characteristics of Alice in Wonderland syndrome in a cohort with vestibular migraine. Neurol Clin Pract 2018; 8:389–396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6276353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30564492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teggi R, Colombo B, Albera R, et al. Clinical features, familial history, and migraine precursors in patients with definite vestibular migraine: the vm-phenotypes projects. Headache 2018; 58:534–544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29205326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuralli D, Yildirim F, Akcali DT, et al. Visual and postural motion-evoked dizziness symptoms are predominant in vestibular migraine patients. Pain Med 2018; 19:178–183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29017000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beh SC, Masrour S, Smith SV, Friedman DI. The spectrum of vestibular migraine: clinical features, triggers, and examination findings. Headache 2019; 59:727–740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30737783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AS, Nham B, Bradshaw AP, et al. Clinical, oculographic, and vestibular test characteristics of vestibular migraine. Cephalalgia 2021; 41:1039–1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33938251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Çelebisoy N, Kisabay Ak A, Özdemir HN, et al. Vestibular migraine, demographic and clinical features of 415 patients: a multicenter study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2022; 215:107201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35303515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noseda R. Cerebro-cerebellar networks in migraine symptoms and headache. Front Pain Res (Lausanne) 2022; 3:940923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35910262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teggi R, Colombo B, Cugnata F, et al. Phenotypes and clinical subgroups in vestibular migraine: a cross-sectional study with cluster analysis. Neurol Sci 2023; 45:1209–1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronstein AM. Oxford textbook of vertigo and imbalance. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronstein AM, Lempert T. Dizziness: a practical approach to diagnosis and management. 2nd ed.Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuyts F, Bronstein A, Maes L. Guidance and differential diagnosis tool of the dizzy patient: ‘SO STONED’. Moscow: Vertigo Academy International; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seemungal BM, Agrawal Y, Bisdorff A, et al. The Bárány Society position on ’Cervical Dizziness’. J Vestib Res 2022; 32:487–499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36404562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsan N, Bose P, Goadsby PJ. The phenotype of premonitory symptoms and migraine headache triggered with nitroglycerin. Cephalalgia 2016; 36 (1S):53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsan N, Bose PR, Thompson C, et al. Headache and nonheadache symptoms provoked by nitroglycerin in migraineurs: a human pharmacological triggering study. Cephalalgia 2020; 40:828–841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32164428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina R, Rocca MA, Colombo B, et al. Structural brain abnormalities in patients with vestibular migraine. J Neurol 2017; 264:295–303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27888414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond PD. Motion sickness and migraine: optokinetic stimulation increases scalp tenderness, pain sensitivity in the fingers and photophobia. Cephalalgia 2002; 22:117–124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11972579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdin L, Chamberlain F, Cheema S, et al. Motion sickness in migraine and vestibular disorders. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86:585–587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4413807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25118205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber FP. Note on idiosyncrasies and abnormalities in human beings. Proc R Soc Med 1928; 21:1211–1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2102303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19986503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrado M, Demartini C, Greco R, et al. Oculo-vestibular signs in experimentally induced migraine attacks: an exploratory analysis. Neurol Sci 2022; 43:6561–6564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9616776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35953579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaleski-King A, Monfared A. Vestibular migraine and its comorbidities. Otolaryngol Clin North Am 2021; 54:949–958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34294433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin T, Gardi A, Sharon JD. Recent developments in vestibular migraine: a narrative review. Am J Audiol 2023; 32 (3s):739–745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36701806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin T, Gillard D, Abouzari M, et al. Vestibular and auditory manifestations of migraine. Curr Opin Neurol 2022; 35:84–89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34864754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Escamez JA, Dlugaiczyk J, Jacobs J, et al. Accompanying symptoms overlap during attacks in Menière's disease and vestibular migraine. Front Neurol 2014; 5:265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4265699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inui T, Kimura F, Moriyama K, et al. Evaluation of vestibular functions in a case of vestibular migraine with successful treatment with erenumab. Ear Nose Throat J 2023. 1455613231202200.doi:10.1177/01455613231202200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37743840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papez JW. A proposed mechanism of emotion. 1937. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci 1995; 7:103–112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7711480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staab JP. Persistent postural-perceptual dizziness. Semin Neurol 2020; 40:130–137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31935771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im JJ, Na S, Jeong H, Chung YA. A review of neuroimaging studies in persistent postural-perceptual dizziness (PPPD). Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2021; 55:53–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto K, Takeuchi T, Ueno T, et al. Effect of central sensitization on dizziness-related symptoms of persistent postural-perceptual dizziness. Biopsychosoc Med 2022; 16:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staab JP, Eckhardt-Henn A, Horii A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for persistent postural-perceptual dizziness (PPPD): consensus document of the committee for the Classification of Vestibular Disorders of the Bárány Society. J Vestib Res 2017; 27:191–208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9249299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29036855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hüfner K, Sperner-Unterweger B. Persistent-postural perceptual dizziness (PPPD): yes, it is a psychosomatic condition!. J Vestib Res 2023; 33:279–281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31561401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarna B, Risbud A, Lee A, et al. Migraine features in patients with persistent postural-perceptual dizziness. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol 2021; 130:1326–1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8487433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33813915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi C, Morita Y, Kitazawa M, et al. A validated questionnaire to assess the severity of persistent postural-perceptual dizziness (PPPD): the Niigata PPPD Questionnaire (NPQ). Otol Neurotol 2019; 40:e747–e752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6641087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31219964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Ajona D, Villar-Martinez MD, Goadsby PJ. PPPD and vestibular migraine. How can we differentiate between these entities? In: 17th European Headache Conference; Barcelona; 6–9 December 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffaelli E, Jr, Menon AD. Migraine and the limbic system. Headache 1975; 15:69–78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1132993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furman JM, Marcus DA, Balaban CD. Rizatriptan reduces vestibular-induced motion sickness in migraineurs. J Headache Pain 2011; 12:81–88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20862509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gecse K, Édes AE, Nagy T, et al. Citalopram neuroendocrine challenge shows altered tryptophan and kynurenine metabolism in migraine. Cells 2022; 11:2258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35883701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard DM, Dawes MA, Mathias CW, et al. L-Tryptophan: basic metabolic functions, behavioral research and therapeutic indications. Int J Tryptophan Res 2009; 2:45–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2908021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20651948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond PD. Effect of tryptophan depletion on symptoms of motion sickness in migraineurs. Neurology 2005; 65:620–622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsan N, Goadsby P. Biological insights from the premonitory symptoms of migraine. Nat Rev Neurol 2018; 14:699–710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30448858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sicuteri F. Mast cells and their active substances: their role in the pathogenesis of migraine. Headache 1963; 3:86–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14094109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferretti A, Gatto M, Velardi M, et al. Migraine, allergy, and histamine: is there a link? J Clin Med 2023; 12:3566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar-Martinez MD, Cheung D, Moreno-Ajona D, Nagaraj K, Goadsby PJ. Connective tissue, autonomic and autoimmune differences between vestibular migraine and chronic migraine. LP024. European Headache Conference. 2023, Barcelona.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri P, Kazeminasab S, Nejadghaderi SA, et al. Migraine: a review on its history, global epidemiology, risk factors, and comorbidities. Front Neurol 2021; 12:800605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8904749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35281991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers SD, Neff BA, Shepard NT, Staab JP. Comorbidities in vestibular migraine. J Vestib Res 2014; 24:387–395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25564081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stadio A, De Luca P, Koohi N, et al. Neuroinflammatory disorders of the brain and inner ear: a systematic review of auditory function in patients with migraine, multiple sclerosis, and neurodegeneration to support the idea of an innovative ’window of discovery’. Front Neurol 2023; 14:1204132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10471191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37662038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salahi M, Parsa S, Nourmohammadi D, et al. Immunologic aspects of migraine: a review of literature. Front Neurol 2022; 13:944791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmioglu N, Mortlock S, Ghiasi M, et al. The genetic basis of endometriosis and comorbidity with other pain and inflammatory conditions. Nat Genet 2023; 55:423–436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10042257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36914876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendik EM, Tinkle BT, Al-shuik E, et al. Joint hypermobility syndrome: a common clinical disorder associated with migraine in women. Cephalalgia 2011; 31:603–613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21278238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puledda F, Viganò A, Celletti C, et al. A study of migraine characteristics in joint hypermobility syndrome a.k.a. Ehlers-Danlos syndrome, hypermobility type. Neurol Sci 2015; 36:1417–1424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25791889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandyala A, Dougherty C. Dermatologic symptoms and syndromes associated with headache. Curr Pain Headache Rep 2022; 26:719–723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36066692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiiski V, Ukkola-Vuoti L, Vikkula J, et al. Effect of disease severity on comorbid conditions in atopic dermatitis: nationwide registry-based investigation in Finnish adults. Acta Derm Venereol 2023; 103:adv00882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10010184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36883876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurin M, Elangovan A, Alikhan MM, et al. Irritable bowel syndrome is strongly associated with the primary and idiopathic mast cell disorders. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2022; 34:e14265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9191257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aupiais C, Wanin S, Romanello S, et al. Association between migraine and atopic diseases in childhood: a potential protective role of anti-allergic drugs. Headache 2017; 57:612–624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28160287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filiz S, Kutluk MG, Uygun DFK. Headache deteriorates the quality of life in children with chronic spontaneous urticaria. Allergol Immunopathol (Madr) 2019; 47:254–259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30686612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccles JA, Owens AP, Mathias CJ, et al. Neurovisceral phenotypes in the expression of psychiatric symptoms. Front Neurosci 2015; 9:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4322642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran R, Wang Z, Saavedra C, et al. Role of Toll-like receptor 4 signaling in mast cell-mediated migraine pain pathway. Mol Pain 2019; 15:1744806919867842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6688145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31342858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlvried LA, Cruz JA, Borghesi LA, Gold MS. Sex-, stress-, and sympathetic postganglionic-dependent changes in identity and proportions of immune cells in the dura. Cephalalgia 2017; 37:36–48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5023503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flook M, Frejo L, Gallego-Martinez A, et al. Differential proinflammatory signature in vestibular migraine and meniere disease. Front Immunol 2019; 10:1229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31214186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S. Dysautonomia, hypermobility spectrum disorders and mast cell activation syndrome as migraine comorbidities. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2023; 23:769–776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beh SC. Vestibular migraine: how to sort it out and what to do about it. J Neuroophthalmol 2019; 39:208–219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31094996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuritzky A, Toglia UJ, Thomas D. Vestibular function in migraine. Headache 1981; 21:110–112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6973556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dürsteler MR. Migraine and the vestibular apparatus (author's transl). J Neurol 1975; 210:253–269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">52695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldingh MI, Ljøstad U, Mygland Å, Monstad P. Comparison of interictal vestibular function in vestibular migraine vs migraine without vertigo. Headache 2013; 53:1123–1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23676003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marano E, Marcelli V, Di Stasio E, et al. Trigeminal stimulation elicits a peripheral vestibular imbalance in migraine patients. Headache 2005; 45:325–331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15836568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H, Chen Y, Huang Q, et al. Differentiating Meniere's disease and vestibular migraine: insights from gadolinium-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging and clinical features. Laryngoscope 2024; 134:426–432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37357969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailani J, Burch RC, Robbins MS. The American Headache Society Consensus Statement: update on integrating new migraine treatments into clinical practice. Headache 2021; 61:1021–1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34160823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diener H-C, Förderreuther S, Kropp P, et al. Treatment of migraine attacks und preventive treatment of migraine, S 1 guideline, 2022, DGN and DMKG, in: Deutsche Gesellschaft für Neurologie (Pub.), Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment in neurology; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth D, Britton Z, Murdin L, et al. Vestibular migraine treatment: a comprehensive practical review. Brain 2022; 145:3741–3754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9679161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byun YJ, Levy DA, Nguyen SA, et al. Treatment of vestibular migraine: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Laryngoscope 2021; 131:186–194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32083732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado Fernández M, Birdi JS, Irving GJ, et al. Pharmacological agents for the prevention of vestibular migraine. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2015; 2015:Cd010600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26093662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salviz M, Yuce T, Acar H, et al. Propranolol and venlafaxine for vestibular migraine prophylaxis: a randomized controlled trial. Laryngoscope 2016; 126:169–174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoskin JL, Fife TD. New Anti-CGRP medications in the treatment of vestibular migraine. Front Neurol 2021; 12:799002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35153979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo CV, Saccà F, Braca S, et al. Anticalcitonin gene-related peptide monoclonal antibodies for the treatment of vestibular migraine: A prospective observational cohort study. Cephalalgia 2023; 43:3331024231161809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36946234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepcha A, Amalanathan S, Augustine AM, et al. Flunarizine in the prophylaxis of migrainous vertigo: a randomized controlled trial. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol 2014; 271:2931–2936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24166742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghdiri F, Togha M, Razeghi Jahromi S, Refaeian F. Cinnarizine for the prophylaxis of migraine associated vertigo: a retrospective study. Springerplus 2014; 3:231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4021030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Dor A, Galbraith K, et al. Pharmacological interventions for acute attacks of vestibular migraine. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2023; 4:Cd015322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37042545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuhauser H, Radtke A, von Brevern M, Lempert T. Zolmitriptan for treatment of migrainous vertigo: a pilot randomized placebo-controlled trial. Neurology 2003; 60:882–883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>