<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39899094</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-6899</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Continuum (Minneapolis, Minn.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Continuum (Minneap Minn)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Classification and Diagnosis of Epilepsy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>14</StartPage><EndPage>37</EndPage><MedlinePgn>14-37</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This article provides readers with a foundational understanding of epilepsy, including epilepsy classification, and presents a strategic approach to the diagnosis of seizures and epilepsy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LATEST DEVELOPMENTS">Epilepsy classification systems have evolved over the years, with improved categorization of seizure types and adoption of more widely accepted and comprehensible terminologies. The International League Against Epilepsy (ILAE) Classification of the Epilepsies (2017) introduces a three-tiered framework. The levels focus on the determination of seizure type, epilepsy type, and identification of epilepsy syndrome, when applicable. The 2017 ILAE classification emphasizes the evaluation of the underlying etiology of epilepsy and the identification of associated comorbidities at all stages of classification. Epilepsy syndromes often have age-dependent symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ESSENTIAL POINTS">A systematic approach to the classification of seizures and epilepsy is essential for the selection of appropriate diagnostic tests and treatment strategies. An accurate classification not only facilitates clinical assessment but has important implications in the determination of prognosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2025 American Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katyal</LastName><ForeName>Roohi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Continuum (Minneap Minn)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9509333</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1080-2371</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epilepsy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012640" MajorTopicYN="N">Seizures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39899094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/cont.0000000000001519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00132979-202502000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wolf P. Has stigma changed? the image of epilepsy in literature. an essay. Epilepsy Behav EB 2022;137(Pt A):108921. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2022.108921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2022.108921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanner AM. Management of psychiatric and neurological comorbidities in epilepsy. Nat Rev Neurol 2016;12(2):106–116. doi:10.1038/nrneurol.2015.243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2015.243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiest KM, Sauro KM, Wiebe S. Prevalence and incidence of epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of international studies. Neurology 2017;88(3):296–303. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000003509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000003509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan TA. Epilepsy: a clinical overview. Am J Med 2021;134(7):840–847. doi:10.1016/j.amjmed.2021.01.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2021.01.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, Acevedo C, Arzimanoglou A, et al. ILAE official report: a practical clinical definition of epilepsy. Epilepsia 2014;55:475–482. doi:10.1111/epi.12550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, van Emde Boas W, Blume W, et al. Epileptic seizures and epilepsy: definitions proposed by the International League Against Epilepsy (ILAE) and the International Bureau for Epilepsy (IBE). Epilepsia 2005;46(4):470–472. doi:10.1111/j.0013-9580.2005.66104.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2005.66104.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, Cross JH, French JA. Operational classification of seizure types by the International League Against Epilepsy: position paper of the ILAE Commission for Classification and Terminology. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):522–530. doi:10.1111/epi.13670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer IE, Berkovic S, Capovilla G. ILAE classification of the epilepsies: position paper of the ILAE Commission for Classification and Terminology. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):512–521. doi:10.1111/epi.13709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer IE, French J, Hirsch E, et al. Classification of the epilepsies: new concepts for discussion and debate—special report of the ILAE Classification Task Force of the Commission for Classification and Terminology. Epilepsia Open 2016;1(1-2):37–44. doi:10.1002/epi4.5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaut H. Classification of the epilepsies: proposal for an international classification. Epilepsia 1969;10:Suppl:14–21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaut H. Clinical and electroencephalographical classification of epileptic seizures. Epilepsia 1970;11(1):102–113. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1157.1970.tb03871.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1970.tb03871.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proposal for revised clinical and electroencephalographic classification of epileptic seizures. From the commission on classification and terminology of the International League Against Epilepsy. Epilepsia 1981;22(4):489–501. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1157.1981.tb06159.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1981.tb06159.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proposal for classification of epilepsies and epileptic syndromes: commission on classification and terminology of the International League Against Epilepsy. Epilepsia 1985;26(3):268–278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proposal for revised classification of epilepsies and epileptic syndromes. Commission on classification and terminology of the International League Against Epilepsy. Epilepsia 1989;30(4):389–399. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1157.1989.tb05316.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1989.tb05316.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lüders HO, Burgess R, Noachtar S. Expanding the international classification of seizures to provide localization information. Neurology 1993;43(9):1650–1655. doi:10.1212/wnl.43.9.1650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.43.9.1650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lüders H, Vaca GFB, Akamatsu N, et al. Classification of paroxysmal events and the four-dimensional epilepsy classification system. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2019;21(1):1–29. doi:10.1684/epd.2019.1033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2019.1033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lüders H, Akamatsu N, Amina S, et al. Critique of the 2017 epileptic seizure and epilepsy classifications. Epilepsia 2019;60(6):1032–1039. doi:10.1111/epi.14699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraballo R, Fejerman N. Management of epilepsy in resource-limited settings. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2015;17(1):13–18; quiz 18. doi:10.1684/epd.2014.0721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2014.0721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand Larsen S, Klok L, Lehn-Schiøler W, Gatej R, Beniczky S. Low-cost portable EEG device for bridging the diagnostic gap in resource-limited areas. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2024;26(5):694–700. doi:10.1002/epd2.20266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epd2.20266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noachtar S, Arnold S. Simple motor seizures: localizing and lateralizing value. In: Textbook of Epilepsy Surgery. 1st ed. Informa Healthcare; 2008:450–461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beniczky S, Tatum WO, Blumenfeld H, et al. Seizure semiology: ILAE glossary of terms and their significance. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2022;24(3):447–495. doi:10.1684/epd.2022.1430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2022.1430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, Cross JH, D’Souza C, et al. Instruction manual for the ILAE 2017 operational classification of seizure types. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):531–542. doi:10.1111/epi.13671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchin MM, Sakamoto AC. Complex motor seizures: localizing and lateralizing value. In: Textbook of Epilepsy Surgery. 1st ed. Informa Healthcare; 2008:462–478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marashly A, Ewida A, Agarwal R, Younes K, Lüders HO. Ictal motor sequences: lateralization and localization values. Epilepsia 2016;57(3):369–375. doi:10.1111/epi.13322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janszky J, Fogarasi A, Jokeit H, Ebner A. Lateralizing value of unilateral motor and somatosensory manifestations in frontal lobe seizures. Epilepsy Res 2001;43(2):125–133. doi:10.1016/s0920-1211(00)00186-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0920-1211(00)00186-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katyal R, Kubota T, De Georgia M, Lüders HO, Fernandez-Baca Vaca G. Bilateral tonic seizures vs. bilateral tonic events in critically ill patients: differences in semiology. Seizure 2023;109:5–11. doi:10.1016/j.seizure.2023.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2023.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayerstein J, McGonigal A, Pizzo F, et al. Quantitative analysis of hyperkinetic seizures and correlation with seizure onset zone. Epilepsia 2020;61(5):1019–1026. doi:10.1111/epi.16510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbadis S. Special seizures: localizing and lateralizing value. In: Textbook of Epilepsy Surgery. 1st ed. Informa Healthcare; 2008:488–491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unterberger I, Trinka E, Kaplan PW, et al. Generalized nonmotor (absence) seizures-what do absence, generalized, and nonmotor mean? Epilepsia 2018;59(3):523–529. doi:10.1111/epi.13996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortez MA, McKerlie C, Snead OC. A model of atypical absence seizures: EEG, pharmacology, and developmental characterization. Neurology 2001;56(3):341–349. doi:10.1212/wnl.56.3.341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.56.3.341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirrell EC, Nabbout R, Scheffer IE, et al. Methodology for classification and definition of epilepsy syndromes with list of syndromes: Report of the ILAE Task Force on Nosology and Definitions. Epilepsia 2022;63(6):1333–1348. doi:10.1111/epi.17237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specchio N, Wirrell EC, Scheffer IE, et al. International League Against Epilepsy classification and definition of epilepsy syndromes with onset in childhood: position paper by the ILAE Task Force on Nosology and Definitions. Epilepsia 2022;63(6):1398–1442. doi:10.1111/epi.17241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuberi SM, Wirrell E, Yozawitz E, et al. ILAE classification and definition of epilepsy syndromes with onset in neonates and infants: position statement by the ILAE Task Force on Nosology and Definitions. Epilepsia 2022;63(6):1349–1397. doi:10.1111/epi.17239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riney K, Bogacz A, Somerville E, et al. International League Against Epilepsy classification and definition of epilepsy syndromes with onset at a variable age: position statement by the ILAE Task Force on Nosology and Definitions. Epilepsia 2022;63(6):1443–1474. doi:10.1111/epi.17240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch E, French J, Scheffer IE, et al. ILAE definition of the idiopathic generalized epilepsy syndromes: position statement by the ILAE Task Force on Nosology and Definitions. Epilepsia 2022;63(6):1475–1499. doi:10.1111/epi.17236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento FA, Friedman D, Peters JM, et al. Focal epilepsies: update on diagnosis and classification. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2023;25(1):1–17. doi:10.1002/epd2.20045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epd2.20045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yacubian EMT, Kakooza-Mwesige A, Singh G, et al. Common infectious and parasitic diseases as a cause of seizures: geographic distribution and contribution to the burden of epilepsy. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2022;24(6):994–1019. doi:10.1684/epd.2022.1491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2022.1491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almannai M, Al Mahmoud RA, Mekki M, El-Hattab AW. Metabolic seizures. Front Neurol 2021;12:640371. doi:10.3389/fneur.2021.640371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.640371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legnani M, Bertinat A, Decima R, et al. Applicability and contribution of the new ILAE 2017 classification of epileptic seizures and epilepsies. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape 2019;21(6):549–554. doi:10.1684/epd.2019.1108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2019.1108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Anand A, Garg D, et al. Use of the International League Against Epilepsy (ILAE) 1989, 2010, and 2017 classification of epilepsy in children in a low-resource setting: a hospital-based cross-sectional study. Epilepsia Open 2020;5(3):397–405. doi:10.1002/epi4.12401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.12401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenow F, Akamatsu N, Bast T, et al. Could the 2017 ILAE and the four-dimensional epilepsy classifications be merged to a new “Integrated Epilepsy Classification”? Seizure 2020;78:31–37. doi:10.1016/j.seizure.2020.02.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2020.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steriade C, Sperling MR, DiVentura B, et al. Proposal for an updated seizure classification framework in clinical trials. Epilepsia 2022;63(3):565–572. doi:10.1111/epi.17120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirfanoglu T, Serdaroglu A, Capraz I, et al. Comparison of ILAE 2010 and semiological seizure classification in children with epilepsy. Epilepsy Res 2017;129:41–50. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.11.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricci L, Boscarino M, Assenza G, et al. Clinical utility of home videos for diagnosing epileptic seizures: a systematic review and practical recommendations for optimal and safe recording. Neurol Sci Off J Ital Neurol Soc Ital Soc Clin Neurophysiol 2021;42(4):1301–1309. doi:10.1007/s10072-021-05040-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05040-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skidmore CT. Neuroimaging in epilepsy. Continuum (Minneap Minn) 2025;31(1, Epilepsy):61–80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sveinsson O, Andersson T, Mattsson P. Clinical risk factors in SUDEP: a nationwide population-based case-control study. Neurology 2020;94(4). doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000008741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000008741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>