<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38934234</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-5391</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of evidence-based medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Evid Based Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnosis and management of inflammatory bowel disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>409</StartPage><EndPage>433</EndPage><MedlinePgn>409-433</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jebm.12626</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is a chronic and relapsing immune-mediated disease of the gastrointestinal tract with a gradually increasing global incidence and prevalence. A prolonged course of IBD leads to a decline in patient quality of life and the creation of a substantial economic burden on society. Owing to the lack of specific diagnostic markers, the diagnosis of IBD still needs a gold standard based on a combination of clinical manifestations, imaging, laboratory, and endoscopic results. Accordingly, the current goals of IBD treatment are to alleviate clinical symptoms and reduce recurrence rates. Therefore, it is imperative to develop a standard set of procedures to diagnose and treat IBD. In this review, we summarize prominent and emerging studies, outline classical and contemporary approaches to diagnosing and managing IBD, and integrate multiple guidelines. Furthermore, we propose the possibility of establishing an early and comprehensive diagnostic workflow and personalized management strategy in the future. We aim to enhance the quality and standardization of diagnostic and treatment procedures for IBD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>© 2024 Chinese Cochrane Center, West China Hospital of Sichuan University and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yushan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Huatian</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center of Gerontology and Geriatrics, National Clinical Research Center for Geriatrics, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3281-4661</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lab of Inflammatory Bowel Disease, Frontiers Science Center for Disease-Related Molecular Network, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021YFH0189</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan International Science and Technology Innovation Cooperation/Hong Kong/Macao/Taiwan Science and Technology Innovation Cooperation Project</Agency><Country /></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022NSFSC1363</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan International Science Foundation Project</Agency><Country /></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023YFS0279</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country /></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023YFS0287</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country /></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021HXFH065</GrantID><Agency>Project for disciplines of excellence-Clinical Research Incubation Project, West China Hospital, Sichuan University</Agency><Country /></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Evid Based Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101497477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-5391</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combined diagnostic panels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrating multiple guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">management strategies</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jebm.12626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ng SC, Shi HY, Hamidi N, et al. Worldwide incidence and prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in the 21st century: a systematic review of population‐based studies. Lancet. 2017;390(10114):2769‐2778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen L, Karachalia Sandri A, Fallingborg J, et al. Has the incidence of inflammatory bowel disease peaked? Evidence from the population‐based NorDIBD cohort 1978–2020. Am J Gastroenterol. 2023;118(3):501‐510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N, Bernstein CN. Environmental risk factors for inflammatory bowel disease. United European Gastroenterol J. 2022;10(10):1047‐1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chachu KA, Osterman MT. How to diagnose and treat IBD mimics in the refractory IBD patient who does not have IBD. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2016;22(5):1262‐1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb CA, Kennedy NA, Raine T, et al. British Society of Gastroenterology consensus guidelines on the management of inflammatory bowel disease in adults. Gut. 2019;68(suppl 3):s1‐s106..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bots S, De Voogd F, De Jong M, et al. Point‐of‐care intestinal ultrasound in IBD patients: disease management and diagnostic yield in a real‐world cohort and proposal of a point‐of‐care algorithm. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16(4):606‐615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Rosentreter R, Delisle M, et al. Systematic review: defining, diagnosing and monitoring small bowel strictures in Crohn's disease on intestinal ultrasound. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2024;59(8):928‐940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimola J, Torres J, Kumar S, Taylor SA, Kucharzik T. Recent advances in clinical practice: advances in cross‐sectional imaging in inflammatory bowel disease. Gut. 2022;71(12):2587‐2597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conrad K, Roggenbuck D, Laass MW. Diagnosis and classification of ulcerative colitis. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;13(4‐5):463‐466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendid B, Cornu M, Cordier C, Bouckaert J, Colombel JF, Poulain D. From ASCA breakthrough in Crohn's disease and Candida albicans research to thirty years of investigations about their meaning in human health. Autoimmun Rev. 2023;23(2):103486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic A, Bakiri L, Wagner EF, Tilg H, Adolph TE. Calprotectin: from biomarker to biological function. Gut. 2021;70(10):1978‐1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgart DC, Sandborn WJ. Inflammatory bowel disease: clinical aspects and established and evolving therapies. Lancet. 2007;369(9573):1641‐1657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zeng Z, Mukherjee A, Shen B. Molecular diagnosis and classification of inflammatory bowel disease. Expert Rev Mol Diagn. 2018;18(10):867‐886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z, Mukherjee A, Zhang H. From genetics to epigenetics, roles of epigenetics in inflammatory bowel disease. Front Genet. 2019;10:1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maaser C, Sturm A, Vavricka SR, et al. ECCO‐ESGAR guideline for diagnostic assessment in IBD part 1: initial diagnosis, monitoring of known IBD, detection of complications. J Crohns Colitis. 2019;13(2):144‐164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veauthier B, Hornecker JR. Crohn's disease: diagnosis and management. Am Fam Physician. 2018;98(11):661‐669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungaro R, Mehandru S, Allen PB, Peyrin‐Biroulet L, Colombel JF. Ulcerative colitis. Lancet. 2017;389(10080):1756‐1770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg MS, Satsangi J, Ahmad T, et al. Toward an integrated clinical, molecular and serological classification of inflammatory bowel disease: report of a Working Party of the 2005 Montreal World Congress of Gastroenterology. Can J Gastroenterol. 2005;19(suppl A):5A‐36A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magro F, Langner C, Driessen A, et al. European consensus on the histopathology of inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2013;7(10):827‐851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn S, Eisenstein S. Inflammatory bowel disease presentation and diagnosis. Surg Clin North Am. 2019;99(6):1051‐1062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine KD, Schiller LR. AGA technical review on the evaluation and management of chronic diarrhea. Gastroenterology. 1999;116(6):1464‐1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vavricka SR, Brun L, Ballabeni P, et al. Frequency and risk factors for extraintestinal manifestations in the Swiss inflammatory bowel disease cohort. Am J Gastroenterol. 2011;106(1):110‐119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogler G, Singh A, Kavanaugh A, Rubin DT. Extraintestinal manifestations of inflammatory bowel disease: current concepts, treatment, and implications for disease management. Gastroenterology. 2021;161(4):1118‐1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vavricka SR, Rogler G, Gantenbein C, et al. Chronological order of appearance of extraintestinal manifestations relative to the time of IBD diagnosis in the Swiss inflammatory bowel disease cohort. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2015;21(8):1794‐1800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman RM, Sharpe MD, Jagger JE, et al. 36th International symposium on intensive care and emergency medicine: Brussels, Belgium. Crit Care. 2016;20(suppl 2):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkins T, Jarvis K, Patel J. Diagnosis and management of Crohn's disease. Am Fam Physician. 2011;84(12):1365‐1375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrin‐Biroulet L, Reinisch W, Colombel JF, et al. Clinical disease activity, C‐reactive protein normalisation and mucosal healing in Crohn's disease in the SONIC trial. Gut. 2014;63(1):88‐95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres J, Mehandru S, Colombel JF, Peyrin‐Biroulet L. Crohn's disease. Lancet. 2017;389(10080):1741‐1755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Zhu M, Luo C, et al. High level of IgG4 as a biomarker for a new subset of inflammatory bowel disease. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):10018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray C, Bell LN, Liang H, et al. Erythrocyte sedimentation rate and C‐reactive protein measurements and their relevance in clinical medicine. WMJ. 2016;115(6):317‐321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagan EA, Dyck RF, Maton PN, et al. Serum levels of C‐reactive protein in Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis. Eur J Clin Invest. 1982;12(4):351‐359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosli MH, Zou G, Garg SK, et al. C‐reactive protein, fecal calprotectin, and stool lactoferrin for detection of endoscopic activity in symptomatic inflammatory bowel disease patients: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2015;110(6):802‐819. quiz 820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakurai T, Saruta M. Positioning and usefulness of biomarkers in inflammatory bowel disease. Digestion. 2023;104(1):30‐41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poullis AP, Zar S, Sundaram KK, et al. A new, highly sensitive assay for C‐reactive protein can aid the differentiation of inflammatory bowel disorders from constipation‐ and diarrhoea‐predominant functional bowel disorders. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2002;14(4):409‐412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menees SB, Powell C, Kurlander J, Goel A, Chey WD. A meta‐analysis of the utility of C‐reactive protein, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, fecal calprotectin, and fecal lactoferrin to exclude inflammatory bowel disease in adults with IBS. Am J Gastroenterol. 2015;110(3):444‐454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solem CA, Loftus EV, jr, Tremaine WJ, Harmsen WS, Zinsmeister AR, Sandborn WJ. Correlation of C‐reactive protein with clinical, endoscopic, histologic, and radiographic activity in inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2005;11(8):707‐712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Mack DR, Hyams J, et al. C‐reactive protein (CRP), erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) or both? A systematic evaluation in pediatric ulcerative colitis. J Crohns Colitis. 2011;5(5):423‐429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtman GA, Lisman‐van Leeuwen Y, Reitsma JB, Berger MY. Noninvasive tests for inflammatory bowel disease: a meta‐analysis. Pediatrics. 2016;137(1):e20152126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang M, Zeng Z, Chen K, et al. Enterogenous microbiotic markers in the differential diagnosis of Crohn's disease and intestinal tuberculosis. Front Immunol. 2022;13:820891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendid B, Quinton JF, Charrier G, et al. Anti‐Saccharomyces cerevisiae mannan antibodies in familial Crohn's disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 1998;93(8):1306‐1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruemmele FM, Targan SR, Levy G, Dubinsky M, Braun J, Seidman EG. Diagnostic accuracy of serological assays in pediatric inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 1998;115(4):822‐829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annese V, Andreoli A, Andriulli A, et al. Familial expression of anti‐Saccharomyces cerevisiae mannan antibodies in Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis: a GISC study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2001;96(8):2407‐2412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Song Y, Yang W, et al. ASCA, ANCA, ALCA and many more: are they useful in the diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease? Dig Dis. 2016;34(1‐2):90‐97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dotan I, Fishman S, Dgani Y, et al. Antibodies against laminaribioside and chitobioside are novel serologic markers in Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 2006;131(2):366‐378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese GE, Constantinides VA, Simillis C, et al. Diagnostic precision of anti‐Saccharomyces cerevisiae antibodies and perinuclear antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies in inflammatory bowel disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2006;101(10):2410‐2422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Schaik FD, Oldenburg B, Hart AR, et al. Serological markers predict inflammatory bowel disease years before the diagnosis. Gut. 2013;62(5):683‐688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands BE. Biomarkers of inflammation in inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(5):1275‐1285.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Roon AC, Karamountzos L, Purkayastha S, et al. Diagnostic precision of fecal calprotectin for inflammatory bowel disease and colorectal malignancy. Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102(4):803‐813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaneethan U, Vargo JJ, Menon KV, Sanaka MR, Tsai CJ. Impact of balloon‐assisted enteroscopy on the diagnosis and management of suspected and established small‐bowel Crohn's disease. Endosc Int Open. 2014;2(4):E201‐E206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman K, Willis BH, Fraser H, Taylor‐Phillips S, Clarke A. Faecal calprotectin to detect inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and exploratory meta‐analysis of test accuracy. BMJ Open. 2019;9(3):e027428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zittan E, Kelly OB, Gralnek IM, Silverberg MS, Hillary Steinhart A. Fecal calprotectin correlates with active colonic inflammatory bowel disease but not with small intestinal Crohn's disease activity. JGH. 2018;2(5):201‐206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witarto BS, Visuddho V, Witarto AP, Sampurna MTA, Irzaldy A. Performance of fecal S100A12 as a novel non‐invasive diagnostic biomarker for pediatric inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2023;99(5):432‐442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Saikam V, Skrada KA, Merlin D, Iyer SS. Inflammatory bowel disease biomarkers. Med Res Rev. 2022;42(5):1856‐1887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanke‐Labesque F, Pofelski J, Moreau‐Gaudry A, Bessard G, Bonaz B. Urinary leukotriene E4 excretion: a biomarker of inflammatory bowel disease activity. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2008;14(6):769‐774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai Y, Arihiro S, Matsuura T, et al. Prostaglandin E‐major urinary metabolite as a reliable surrogate marker for mucosal inflammation in ulcerative colitis. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2014;20(7):1208‐1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsthuis K, Bipat S, Bennink RJ, Stoker J. Inflammatory bowel disease diagnosed with US, MR, scintigraphy, and CT: meta‐analysis of prospective studies. Radiology. 2008;247(1):64‐79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panes J, Bouhnik Y, Reinisch W, et al. Imaging techniques for assessment of inflammatory bowel disease: joint ECCO and ESGAR evidence‐based consensus guidelines. J Crohns Colitis. 2013;7(7):556‐585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maconi G, Nylund K, Ripolles T, et al. EFSUMB recommendations and clinical guidelines for intestinal ultrasound (GIUS) in inflammatory bowel diseases. Ultraschall Med. 2018;39(3):304‐317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese E, Kucharzik T, Maaser C, et al. Real‐time interobserver agreement in bowel ultrasonography for diagnostic assessment in patients with Crohn's disease: an international multicenter study. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2018;24(9):2001‐2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorzi F, Stasi E, Bevivino G, et al. A sonographic lesion index for Crohn's disease helps monitor changes in transmural bowel damage during therapy. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;12(12):2071‐2077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panés J, Bouzas R, Chaparro M, et al. Systematic review: the use of ultrasonography, computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging for the diagnosis, assessment of activity and abdominal complications of Crohn's disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2011;34(2):125‐145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen GR, Wilkens R, Boysen T, et al. The knowledge and skills needed to perform intestinal ultrasound for inflammatory bowel diseases‐an international Delphi consensus survey. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56(2):263‐270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao N, Kumar S, Taylor S, Plumb A. Diagnostic pathways in Crohn's disease. Clin Radiol. 2019;74(8):578‐591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimola J, Ordás I, Rodriguez S, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging for evaluation of Crohn's disease: validation of parameters of severity and quantitative index of activity. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2011;17(8):1759‐1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krugliak Cleveland N, St‐Pierre J, Kellar A, Rubin DT. Clinical application of intestinal ultrasound in inflammatory bowel disease. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2024;26(2):31‐40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SA, Mallett S, Bhatnagar G, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of magnetic resonance enterography and small bowel ultrasound for the extent and activity of newly diagnosed and relapsed Crohn's disease (METRIC): a multicentre trial. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;3(8):548‐558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annese V, Daperno M, Rutter MD, et al. European evidence based consensus for endoscopy in inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2013;7(12):982‐1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharadwaj S, Tandon P, Kulkarni G, Rivas J, Charles R. The role of endoscopy in inflammatory bowel disease. J Dig Dis. 2015;16(12):689‐698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Haens G, Geboes K, Peeters M, Baert F, Ectors N, Rutgeerts P. Patchy cecal inflammation associated with distal ulcerative colitis: a prospective endoscopic study. Am J Gastroenterol. 1997;92(8):1275‐1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson P, Papadakis KA. Endoscopic evaluation of patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2008;14(9):1287‐1297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pera A, Bellando P, Caldera D, et al. Colonoscopy in inflammatory bowel disease. Diagnostic accuracy and proposal of an endoscopic score. Gastroenterology. 1987;92(1):181‐185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CQ, Xie XJ, Yu T, et al. Classification of inflammation activity in ulcerative colitis by confocal laser endomicroscopy. Am J Gastroenterol. 2010;105(6):1391‐1396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tontini GE, Rath T, Neumann H. Advanced gastrointestinal endoscopic imaging for inflammatory bowel diseases. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22(3):1246‐1259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mowat C, Cole A, Windsor A, et al. Guidelines for the management of inflammatory bowel disease in adults. Gut. 2011;60(5):571‐607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher G, Kollberg B, Sandstedt B. A prospective study of first attacks of inflammatory bowel disease and infectious colitis. Histologic course during the 1st year after presentation. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1994;29(4):318‐332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langner C, Magro F, Driessen A, et al. The histopathological approach to inflammatory bowel disease: a practice guide. Virchows Arch. 2014;464(5):511‐527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley E, Jenkins D, Campbell F, Warren B. How could pathologists improve the initial diagnosis of colitis? Evidence from an international workshop. J Clin Pathol. 2002;55(12):955‐960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiceland CM, Lodhia N. Endoscopy in inflammatory bowel disease: role in diagnosis, management, and treatment. World J Gastroenterol. 2018;24(35):4014‐4020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomollón F, Dignass A, Annese V, et al. 3rd European evidence‐based consensus on the diagnosis and management of Crohn's disease 2016: part 1: diagnosis and medical management. J Crohns Colitis. 2017;11(1):3‐25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annunziata ML, Caviglia R, Papparella LG, Cicala M. Upper gastrointestinal involvement of Crohn's disease: a prospective study on the role of upper endoscopy in the diagnostic work‐up. Dig Dis Sci. 2012;57(6):1618‐1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XL, Shen JT, Li YP, et al. Capsule endoscopy in diagnosis of small bowel diseases: a health technology assessment. J Evid Based Med. 2014;7(2):84‐102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionisio PM, Gurudu SR, Leighton JA, et al. Capsule endoscopy has a significantly higher diagnostic yield in patients with suspected and established small‐bowel Crohn's disease: a meta‐analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2010;105(6):1240‐1248. quiz 1249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheon JH, Kim YS, Lee IS, et al. Can we predict spontaneous capsule passage after retention? A nationwide study to evaluate the incidence and clinical outcomes of capsule retention. Endoscopy. 2007;39(12):1046‐1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magro F, Gionchetti P, Eliakim R, et al. Third European evidence‐based consensus on diagnosis and management of ulcerative colitis. Part 1: definitions, diagnosis, extra‐intestinal manifestations, pregnancy, cancer surveillance, surgery, and ileo‐anal pouch disorders. J Crohns Colitis. 2017;11(6):649‐670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyams J, Damaraju L, Blank M, et al. Induction and maintenance therapy with infliximab for children with moderate to severe ulcerative colitis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;10(4):391‐399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobatón T, Bessissow T, De Hertogh G, et al. The Modified Mayo Endoscopic Score (MMES): a new index for the assessment of extension and severity of endoscopic activity in ulcerative colitis patients. J Crohns Colitis. 2015;9(10):846‐852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walmsley RS, Ayres RC, Pounder RE, Allan RN. A simple clinical colitis activity index. Gut. 1998;43(1):29‐32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss AC, Farrell RJ. Infliximab for induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2006;131(5):1649‐1651. discussion 1651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeire S, Schreiber S, Sandborn WJ, Dubois C, Rutgeerts P. Correlation between the Crohn's disease activity and Harvey‐Bradshaw indices in assessing Crohn's disease severity. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2010;8(4):357‐363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey RF, Bradshaw JM. A simple index of Crohn's‐disease activity. Lancet. 1980;1(8167):514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mary JY, Modigliani R. Development and validation of an endoscopic index of the severity for Crohn's disease: a prospective multicentre study. Groupe d'Etudes Thérapeutiques des Affections Inflammatoires du Tube Digestif (GETAID). Gut. 1989;30(7):983‐989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best WR, Becktel JM, Singleton JW. Development of a Crohn's disease activity index. National Cooperative Crohn's Disease Study. Gastroenterology. 1976;70(3):439‐444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajendran M, Loganathan P, Catinella AP, Hashash JG. A comprehensive review and update on Crohn's disease. Dis Mon. 2018;64(2):20‐57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best WR. Predicting the Crohn's disease activity index from the Harvey‐Bradshaw index. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2006;12(4):304‐310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daperno M, D'Haens G, Van Assche G, et al. Development and validation of a new, simplified endoscopic activity score for Crohn's disease: the SES‐CD. Gastrointest Endosc. 2004;60(4):505‐512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouillon L, Laurent V, Pouillon M, et al. Diffusion‐weighted MRI in inflammatory bowel disease. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;3(6):433‐443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oussalah A, Laurent V, Bruot O, et al. Diffusion‐weighted magnetic resonance without bowel preparation for detecting colonic inflammation in inflammatory bowel disease. Gut. 2010;59(8):1056‐1065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allocca M, Craviotto V, Dell'Avalle C, et al. Bowel ultrasound score is accurate in assessing response to therapy in patients with Crohn's disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;55(4):446‐454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sævik F, Eriksen R, Eide GE, Gilja OH, Nylund K. Development and validation of a simple ultrasound activity score for Crohn's disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15(1):115‐124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosli MH, Feagan BG, Zou G, et al. Development and validation of a histological index for UC. Gut. 2017;66(1):50‐58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchal‐Bressenot A, Salleron J, Boulagnon‐Rombi C, et al. Development and validation of the Nancy histological index for UC. Gut. 2017;66(1):43‐49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak G, Parker CE, Pai RK, et al. Histologic scoring indices for evaluation of disease activity in Crohn's disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;7(7), Cd012351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davatchi F, Chams‐Davatchi C, Shams H, et al. Behcet's disease: epidemiology, clinical manifestations, and diagnosis. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2017;13(1):57‐65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolaus S, Schreiber S. Diagnostics of inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 2007;133(5):1670‐1689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DT, Ananthakrishnan AN, Siegel CA, Sauer BG, Long MD. ACG clinical guideline: ulcerative colitis in adults. Am J Gastroenterol. 2019;114(3):384‐413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roda G, Chien Ng S, Kotze PG, et al. Crohn's disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6(1):22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veyrard P, Nancey S, Roblin X. Editorial: 5‐ASA in IBD patients on biologics‐“stop or continue”? Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2021;54(6):843‐844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Kane SV, Khan KJ, et al. Efficacy of 5‐aminosalicylates in Crohn's disease: systematic review and meta‐analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2011;106(4):617‐629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenstein GR, Loftus EV, Isaacs KL, Regueiro MD, Gerson LB, Sands BE. ACG clinical guideline: management of Crohn's disease in adults. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;113(4):481‐517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noureldin M, Cohen‐Mekelburg S, Mahmood A, et al. Trends of 5‐aminosalicylate medication use in patients with Crohn disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2021;27(4):516‐521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Ouyang Q, Wen ZH, et al. Significance of glucocorticoid receptor expression in colonic mucosal cells of patients with ulcerative colitis. World J Gastroenterol. 2005;11(12):1775‐1778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afzali A, Armuzzi A, Bouhnik Y, et al. P393 Patient and physician perspectives on the management of inflammatory bowel disease: role of steroids in the context of biologic therapy. J Crohns Colitis. 2020;14(suppl 1):S366‐S367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waljee AK, Wiitala WL, Govani S, et al. Corticosteroid use and complications in a us inflammatory bowel disease cohort. PLoS One. 2016;11(6):e0158017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selinger CP, Parkes GC, Bassi A, et al. Assessment of steroid use as a key performance indicator in inflammatory bowel disease‐analysis of data from 2385 UK patients. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2019;50(9):1009‐1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selinger CP, Parkes GC, Bassi A, et al. A multi‐centre audit of excess steroid use in 1176 patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2017;46(10):964‐973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targownik LE, Nugent Z, Singh H, Bernstein CN. Prevalence of and outcomes associated with corticosteroid prescription in inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2014;20(4):622‐630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosiou K, Carbonell J, Dolby V, Monfared N, Raine T, Selinger CP. Sources of excess steroid prescriptions and clinical adverse outcomes associated with steroid excess in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: the Leeds IBD Steroids study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56(3):501‐509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison N, Humes R, Singla M. Skip, stop, switch, and spare: steroid therapy in inflammatory bowel disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116(9):1819‐1821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chande N, Patton PH, Tsoulis DJ, Thomas BS, MacDonald JK. Azathioprine or 6‐mercaptopurine for maintenance of remission in Crohn's disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(10):Cd000067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres J, Bonovas S, Doherty G, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in Crohn's disease: medical treatment. J Crohns Colitis. 2020;14(1):4‐22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raine T, Bonovas S, Burisch J, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in ulcerative colitis: medical treatment. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16(1):2‐17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezazadeh Ardabili A, Jeuring S, Mujagic Z, et al. Classic drugs in the time of new drugs: real‐world, long‐term outcomes of thiopurine monotherapy in 1016 patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56(6):1030‐1043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Mao R, Zhang SH, et al. Safety profile of thiopurines in Crohn disease: analysis of 893 patient‐years follow‐up in a Southern China cohort. Medicine. 2015;94(41):e1513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein JD, Nguyen GC, Kupfer SS, Falck‐Ytter Y, Singh S. American gastroenterological association institute guideline on therapeutic drug monitoring in inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterology. 2017;153(3):827‐834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SK, Hong M, Baek J, et al. A common missense variant in NUDT15 confers susceptibility to thiopurine‐induced leukopenia. Nat Genet. 2014;46(9):1017‐1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gearry RB, Barclay ML. Azathioprine and 6‐mercaptopurine pharmacogenetics and metabolite monitoring in inflammatory bowel disease. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2005;20(8):1149‐1157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feagan BG, Rochon J, Fedorak RN, et al. Methotrexate for the treatment of Crohn's disease. The North American Crohn's Study Group Investigators. N Engl J Med. 1995;332(5):292‐297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald JW, Wang Y, Tsoulis DJ, MacDonald JK, Feagan BG. Methotrexate for induction of remission in refractory Crohn's disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014(8):Cd003459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen OH, Steenholdt C, Juhl CB, Rogler G. Efficacy and safety of methotrexate in the management of inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of randomized, controlled trials. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;20:100271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Travis SP, Griffiths AM, et al. Consensus for managing acute severe ulcerative colitis in children: a systematic review and joint statement from ECCO, ESPGHAN, and the Porto IBD Working Group of ESPGHAN. Am J Gastroenterol. 2011;106(4):574‐588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narula N, Marshall JK, Colombel JF, et al. Systematic review and meta‐analysis: infliximab or cyclosporine as rescue therapy in patients with severe ulcerative colitis refractory to steroids. Am J Gastroenterol. 2016;111(4):477‐491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodríguez‐Lago I, Castro‐Poceiro J, Fernández‐Clotet A, et al. Tacrolimus induces short‐term but not long‐term clinical response in inflammatory bowel disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;51(9):870‐879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogata H, Matsui T, Nakamura M, et al. A randomised dose finding study of oral tacrolimus (FK506) therapy in refractory ulcerative colitis. Gut. 2006;55(9):1255‐1262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzerini M, Martelossi S, Magazzù G, et al. Effect of thalidomide on clinical remission in children and adolescents with refractory Crohn disease: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2164‐2173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramuzzo M, Ventura A, Martelossi S, Lazzerini M. Thalidomide for inflammatory bowel disease: systematic review. Medicine. 2016;95(30):e4239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzerini M, Martelossi S, Magazzù G, et al. Effect of thalidomide on clinical remission in children and adolescents with ulcerative colitis refractory to other immunosuppressives: pilot randomized clinical trial. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2015;21(8):1739‐1749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramuzzo M, Giudici F, Arrigo S, et al. Efficacy and tolerance of thalidomide in patients with very early onset inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2024;30(1):20‐28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raine T, Verstockt B, Kopylov U, et al. ECCO topical review: refractory inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15(10):1605‐1620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Lin ZW, Zhang M, et al. The efficacy and safety of thalidomide in the treatment of refractory Crohn's disease in adults: a double‐center, double‐blind, randomized‐controlled trial. Gastroenterol Rep. 2022;10:goac052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein JD, Isaacs KL, Schneider Y, Siddique SM, Falck‐Ytter Y, Singh S. AGA clinical practice guidelines on the management of moderate to severe ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2020;158(5):1450‐1461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Proctor D, Scott FI, Falck‐Ytter Y, Feuerstein JD. AGA technical review on the medical management of moderate to severe luminal and perianal fistulizing Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(7):2512‐2556.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narula N, Wong ECL, Dulai PS, et al. Comparative efficacy and rapidity of action for infliximab vs ustekinumab in biologic naïve Crohn's disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20(7):1579‐1587.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alric H, Amiot A, Kirchgesner J, et al. The effectiveness of either ustekinumab or vedolizumab in 239 patients with Crohn's disease refractory to anti‐tumour necrosis factor. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;51(10):948‐957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biemans VBC, van der Woude CJ, Dijkstra G, et al. Ustekinumab is associated with superior effectiveness outcomes compared to vedolizumab in Crohn's disease patients with prior failure to anti‐TNF treatment. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;52(1):123‐134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulai PS, Boland BS, Singh S, et al. Development and validation of a scoring system to predict outcomes of vedolizumab treatment in patients with Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 2018;155(3):687‐695.e10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein JD, Ho EY, Shmidt E, et al. AGA clinical practice guidelines on the medical management of moderate to severe luminal and perianal fistulizing Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(7):2496‐2508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanchlani N, Lin S, Bewshea C, et al. Mechanisms and management of loss of response to anti‐TNF therapy for patients with Crohn's disease: 3‐year data from the prospective, multicentre PANTS cohort study. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2024;9(6):521‐538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vande Casteele N, Jairath V, Jeyarajah J, et al. Development and validation of a clinical decision support tool that incorporates pharmacokinetic data to predict endoscopic healing in patients treated with infliximab. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(6):1209‐1217.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SA‐O, Chanchlani NA‐O, Carbery I, et al. Understanding anti‐TNF treatment failure: does serum triiodothyronine‐to‐thyroxine (T3/T4) ratio predict therapeutic outcome to anti‐TNF therapies in biologic‐naïve patients with active luminal Crohn's disease? Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56(5):783‐793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo G, Caviglia GP, Ravera A, et al. NAMPT and NAPRT serum levels predict response to anti‐TNF therapy in inflammatory bowel disease. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;1(10):1116862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messadeg L, Hordonneau C, Bouguen G, et al. Early transmural response assessed using magnetic resonance imaging could predict sustained clinical remission and prevent bowel damage in patients with Crohn's disease treated with anti‐tumour necrosis factor therapy. J Crohns Colitis. 2020;14(11):1524‐1534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulai PS, Singh S, Vande Casteele N, et al. Development and validation of clinical scoring tool to predict outcomes of treatment with vedolizumab in patients with ulcerative colitis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18(13):2952‐2961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danese S, Solitano V, Jairath V, Peyrin‐Biroulet L. The future of drug development for inflammatory bowel disease: the need to ACT (advanced combination treatment). Gut. 2022;71(12):2380‐2387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glassner K, Oglat A, Duran A, et al. The use of combination biological or small molecule therapy in inflammatory bowel disease: a retrospective cohort study. J Dig Dis. 2020;21(5):264‐271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goessens L, Colombel JF, Outtier A, et al. Safety and efficacy of combining biologics or small molecules for inflammatory bowel disease or immune‐mediated inflammatory diseases: a European retrospective observational study. United European Gastroenterol J. 2021;9(10):1136‐1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombel JF, Sandborn WJ, Reinisch W, et al. Infliximab, azathioprine, or combination therapy for Crohn's disease. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(15):1383‐1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panaccione R, Ghosh S, Middleton S, et al. Combination therapy with infliximab and azathioprine is superior to monotherapy with either agent in ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2014;146(2):392‐400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombel JF, Adedokun OJ, Gasink C, et al. Combination therapy with infliximab and azathioprine improves infliximab pharmacokinetic features and efficacy: a post hoc analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;17(8):1525‐1532.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands BE, Kozarek R, Spainhour J, et al. Safety and tolerability of concurrent natalizumab treatment for patients with Crohn's disease not in remission while receiving infliximab. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2007;13(1):2‐11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buer LCT, Høivik ML, Warren DJ, Medhus AW, Moum BA. Combining anti‐TNF‐α and vedolizumab in the treatment of inflammatory bowel disease: a case series. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2018;24(5):997‐1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribaldone DG, Pellicano R, Vernero M, et al. Dual biological therapy with anti‐TNF, vedolizumab or ustekinumab in inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review with pool analysis. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2019;54(4):407‐413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang E, Panaccione N, Whitmire N, et al. Efficacy and safety of simultaneous treatment with two biologic medications in refractory Crohn's disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;51(11):1031‐1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olbjørn C, Rove JB, Jahnsen J. Combination of biological agents in moderate to severe pediatric inflammatory bowel disease: a case series and review of the literature. Paediatr Drugs. 2020;22(4):409‐416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Privitera G, Onali S, Pugliese D, et al. Dual targeted therapy: a possible option for the management of refractory inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15(2):335‐339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwapisz L, Raffals LE, Bruining DH, et al. Combination biologic therapy in inflammatory bowel disease: experience from a tertiary care center. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(3):616‐617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alayo QA, Khatiwada A, Patel A, et al. Effectiveness and safety of combining tofacitinib with a biologic in patients with refractory inflammatory bowel diseases. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2021;27(10):1698‐1702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llano EM, Shrestha S, Burstein E, Boktor M, Fudman DI. Favorable outcomes combining vedolizumab with other biologics or tofacitinib for treatment of inflammatory bowel disease. Crohns Colitis 360. 2021;3(3):otab030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed W, Galati J, Kumar A, et al. Dual biologic or small molecule therapy for treatment of inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20(3):e361‐e379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolinger MT, Spencer EA, Lai J, Dunkin D, Dubinsky MC. Dual biologic and small molecule therapy for the treatment of refractory pediatric inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2021;27(8):1210‐1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eronen H, Kolehmainen S, Koffert J, et al. Combining biological therapies in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a Finnish multi‐centre study. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2022;57(8):936‐941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SD, Singla A, Harper J, et al. Safety and efficacy of tofacitinib in combination with biologic therapy for refractory Crohn's disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2022;28(2):309‐313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands BE, Feagan BG, Sandborn WJ, et al. Efficacy and safety of combination induction therapy with guselkumab and golimumab in participants with moderately to severely active ulcerative colitis: results through week 12 of a phase 2a randomized, double‐blind, active‐controlled, parallel‐group, multicenter, proof‐of‐concept study. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16(Suppl 1):i042‐i043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thia KT, Sandborn WJ, Harmsen WS, Zinsmeister AR. Risk factors associated with progression to intestinal complications of Crohn's disease in a population‐based cohort. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(4):1147‐1155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrin‐Biroulet L, Loftus EV, jr, Colombel JF, Sandborn WJ. The natural history of adult Crohn's disease in population‐based cohorts. Am J Gastroenterol. 2010;105(2):289‐297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal M, Ebert AC, Poulsen G, et al. Early ileocecal resection for Crohn's disease is associated with improved long‐term outcomes compared with anti‐tumor necrosis factor therapy: a population‐based cohort study. Gastroenterology. 2023;165(4):976‐985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli A, Bonovas S, Burisch J, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in ulcerative colitis: surgical treatment. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16(2):179‐189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhu W, Zuo L, et al. Frequency and risk factors of postoperative recurrence of Crohn's disease after intestinal resection in the Chinese population. J Gastrointest Surg. 2012;16(8):1539‐1547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Yang RP, Chen MH, et al. Risk factors for surgery and postoperative recurrence: analysis of a south China cohort with Crohn's disease. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2012;47(10):1181‐1191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C, Vasu R, Zhang H. The role of long‐chain fatty acids in inflammatory bowel disease. Mediators Inflamm. 2019;2019:8495913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khademi Z, Pourreza S, Amjadifar A, Torkizadeh M, Amirkhizi F. Dietary patterns and risk of inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review of observational studies. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2024; izad297. doi:10.1093/ibd/izad297</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang Y, Ma C, Chen K, et al. The effects of a high‐fat diet on inflammatory bowel disease. Biomolecules. 2023;13(6):905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine A, Rhodes JM, Lindsay JO, et al. Dietary guidance from the international organization for the study of inflammatory bowel diseases. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18(6):1381‐1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulley J, Todd A, Flatley C, Begun J. Malnutrition and quality of life among adult inflammatory bowel disease patients. JGH Open. 2020;4(3):454‐460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijac DD, Janković GL, Jorga J, Krstić MN. Nutritional status in patients with active inflammatory bowel disease: prevalence of malnutrition and methods for routine nutritional assessment. Eur J Intern Med. 2010;21(4):315‐319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff SC, Bager P, Escher J, et al. ESPEN guideline on clinical nutrition in inflammatory bowel disease. Clin Nutr. 2023;42(3):352‐379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuendorf R, Harding A, Stello N, Hanes D, Wahbeh H. Depression and anxiety in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review. J Psychosom Res. 2016;87:70‐80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciberras M, Karmiris K, Nascimento C, et al. Mental health, work presenteeism, and exercise in inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16(8):1197‐1201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolovich C, Bernstein CN, Singh H, et al. Anxiety and depression leads to anti‐tumor necrosis factor discontinuation in inflammatory bowel disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(6):1200‐1208.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levenstein S, Prantera C, Varvo V, et al. Stress and exacerbation in ulcerative colitis: a prospective study of patients enrolled in remission. Am J Gastroenterol. 2000;95(5):1213‐1220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitton A, Sewitch MJ, Peppercorn MA, et al. Psychosocial determinants of relapse in ulcerative colitis: a longitudinal study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2003;98(10):2203‐2208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggott C, Mikocka‐Walus A, Gracie DJ, Ford AC. Efficacy of psychological therapies in people with inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;8(10):919‐931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lores T, Goess C, Mikocka‐Walus A, et al. Integrated psychological care reduces health care costs at a hospital‐based inflammatory bowel disease service. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(1):96‐103.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zoeten EF, Pasternak BA, Mattei P, Kramer RE, Kader HA. Diagnosis and treatment of perianal Crohn disease: nASPGHAN clinical report and consensus statement. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2013;57(3):401‐412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen OH, Rogler G, Hahnloser D, Thomsen O. Diagnosis and management of fistulizing Crohn's disease. Nat Clin Pract Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;6(2):92‐106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DA, Loftus EV, jr, Tremaine WJ, et al. The natural history of fistulizing Crohn's disease in Olmsted County, Minnesota. Gastroenterology. 2002;122(4):875‐880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Göttgens KW, Jeuring SF, Sturkenboom R, et al. Time trends in the epidemiology and outcome of perianal fistulizing Crohn's disease in a population‐based cohort. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;29(5):595‐601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adler J, Lin CC, Gadepalli SK, Dombkowski KJ. Association between steroid‐sparing therapy and the risk of perianal fistulizing complications among young patients with Crohn disease. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(6):e207378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands BE, Anderson FH, Bernstein CN, et al. Infliximab maintenance therapy for fistulizing Crohn's disease. N Engl J Med. 2004;350(9):876‐885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godoy Brewer GM, Salem G, Afzal MA, et al. Ustekinumab is effective for perianal fistulising Crohn's disease: a real‐world experience and systematic review with meta‐analysis. BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2021;8(1):e000702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DA, Peyrin‐Biroulet L, Lasch K, Adsul S, Danese S. Efficacy and safety of 2 vedolizumab intravenous regimens for perianal fistulizing Crohn's disease: eNTERPRISE study. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20(5):1059‐1067.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassin NA, Askari A, Warusavitarne J, et al. Systematic review: the combined surgical and medical treatment of fistulising perianal Crohn's disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2014;40(7):741‐749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Ricciuto A, Lewis A, et al. STRIDE‐II: an update on the selecting therapeutic targets in inflammatory bowel disease (STRIDE) initiative of the international organization for the study of IBD (IOIBD): determining therapeutic goals for treat‐to‐target strategies in IBD. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(5):1570‐1583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Zheng X, Li Y, et al. Exploring patient medication adherence and data mining methods in clinical big data: a contemporary review. J Evid Based Med. 2023;16(3):342‐375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morar PA‐O, Read J, Arora S, et al. Defining the optimal design of the inflammatory bowel disease multidisciplinary team: results from a multicentre qualitative expert‐based study. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2015;6(4):290‐297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morar PA‐O, Sevdalis N, Warusavitarne J, et al. Establishing the aims, format and function for multidisciplinary team‐driven care within an inflammatory bowel disease service: a multicentre qualitative specialist‐based consensus study. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2018;9(1):29‐36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen PF, Van de Vijver E, Fidler V. Faecal calprotectin for screening of patients with suspected inflammatory bowel disease: diagnostic meta‐analysis. BMJ. 2010;341:c3369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z, Jiang M, Li X, Yuan J, Zhang H. Precision medicine in inflammatory bowel disease. Precis Clin Med. 2023;6(4):pbad033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H, Liu Z. The latest breakthrough on genetic characteristics of inflammatory bowel disease in Chinese and other East Asian ancestries. Precis Clin Med. 2023;6(3):pbad017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lange KM, Moutsianas L, Lee JC, et al. Genome‐wide association study implicates immune activation of multiple integrin genes in inflammatory bowel disease. Nat Genet. 2017;49(2):256‐261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F, Wu M, Li R. The significance of long non‐coding RNAs in the pathogenesis, diagnosis and treatment of inflammatory bowel disease. Precis Clin Med. 2023;6(4):pbad031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moret‐Tatay I, Cerrillo E, Sáez‐González E, et al. Identification of epigenetic methylation signatures with clinical value in Crohn's disease. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2019;10(10):e00083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarmakiewicz‐Czaja S, Zielińska M, Sokal A, Filip R. Genetic and epigenetic etiology of inflammatory bowel disease: an update. Genes. 2022;13(12):2388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevy S, Silverberg MS, Lockton S, et al. Combined serological, genetic, and inflammatory markers differentiate non‐IBD, Crohn's disease, and ulcerative colitis patients. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2013;19(6):1139‐1148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilotta AJ, Cong Y. Gut microbiota metabolite regulation of host defenses at mucosal surfaces: implication in precision medicine. Precis Clin Med. 2019;2(2):110‐119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moayyedi P, Surette MG, Kim PT, et al. Fecal microbiota transplantation induces remission in patients with active ulcerative colitis in a randomized controlled trial. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(1):102‐109.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossen NG, Fuentes S, van der Spek MJ, et al. Findings from a randomized controlled trial of fecal transplantation for patients with ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(1):110‐118.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao D, Hotte N, Gillevet P, Madsen K. Fecal microbiota transplantation inducing remission in Crohn's colitis and the associated changes in fecal microbial profile. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2014;48(7):625‐628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeire S, Joossens M, Verbeke K, et al. Donor species richness determines faecal microbiota transplantation success in inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2016;10(4):387‐394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z, Mukherjee A, Varghese AP, Yang XL, Chen S, Zhang H. Roles of G protein‐coupled receptors in inflammatory bowel disease. World J Gastroenterol. 2020;26(12):1242‐1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Mu J, Zhu M, Mukherjee A, Zhang H. Transient receptor potential channels and inflammatory bowel disease. Front Immunol. 2020;11:180.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>