<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41110447</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>406</Volume><Issue>10517</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Community-acquired pneumonia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2371</StartPage><EndPage>2388</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2371-2388</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(25)01493-X</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0140-6736(25)01493-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Community-acquired pneumonia is a major global health challenge that disproportionately affects vulnerable populations, including older people, immunocompromised people, those with chronic conditions, and young children. Once considered solely an acute illness, community-acquired pneumonia is now recognised as a disease with long-term complications, including cardiovascular events, respiratory impairment, and cognitive decline. Advances, such as nucleic acid amplification tests (NAATs) and the broader availability of point-of-care lung ultrasound, allow for rapid pathogen detection and personalised treatment. However, substantial uncertainties remain regarding the role of NAATs, lung ultrasounds, and serum biomarkers in clinical practice. Antibiotics are the cornerstone of community-acquired pneumonia treatment, but the roles of adjunctive therapies, including corticosteroids and immunomodulators, remain incompletely defined. Comprehensive community-acquired pneumonia management emphasises personalised treatment, rehabilitation after the acute episode, routine cardiovascular screening, and strengthening preventive measures, such as vaccination. As precision medicine advances, integrating diagnostics and tailored therapies will improve outcomes and reduce the global burden of community-acquired pneumonia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reyes</LastName><ForeName>Luis Felipe</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unisabana Center for Translational Science, School of Medicine, Universidad de La Sabana, Chía, Colombia; Clinica Universidad de La Sabana, Chía, Colombia; International Severe Acute Respiratory and Emerging Infection Consortium, Pandemic Sciences Institute, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK. Electronic address: luis.reyes5@unisabana.edu.co.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conway Morris</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Perioperative, Acute, Critical Care, and Emergency Medicine Section, University of Cambridge, Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge, UK; JVF Intensive Care Unit, Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serrano-Mayorga</LastName><ForeName>Cristian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinica Universidad de La Sabana, Chía, Colombia; Engineering School, Universidad de la Sabana, Chía, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derde</LastName><ForeName>Lennie P G</ForeName><Initials>LPG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dickson</LastName><ForeName>Robert P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, University of Michigan Health System, Ann Arbor, MI, USA; Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Michigan Medical School, Ann Arbor, MI, USA; Weil Institute for Critical Care Research &amp; Innovation, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin-Loeches</LastName><ForeName>Ignacio</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multidisciplinary Intensive Care Research Organization, St James's Hospital, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000098968" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community-Acquired Pneumonia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071219" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Burden of Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests LFR reports grants or contracts from GSK, Pfizer, and MSD; consulting fees from GSK and Pfizer; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from GSK and Pfizer; payment for expert testimony from GSK and Pfizer; and support for attending meetings and/or travel from GSK and Pfizer. ACM reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Biomerieux, Fischer and Paykel, ThermoFisher, and Boston Scientific, and participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board for Cambridge Infection Diagnostics. CS-M reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Pfizer and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Pfizer. LPGD reports grants or contracts from Horizon 2020; support for attending meetings and/or travel from the European Society of Intensive Care Medicine (ESICIM), the International Symposium on Intensive Care and Emergency Medicine, the European Respiratory Society, and the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center; and a leadership or fiduciary role in other board, society, committee, or advocacy group, paid or unpaid with WHO, ESICIM, the European Clinical Research Alliance for Infectious Diseases, and the Dutch Society for Intensive Care Medicine. IM-L reports consulting fees from Mundipharma and payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from MSD and Gilead. RPD declares no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41110447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(25)01493-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(25)01493-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>